for my birthday this year,
i decided to go on another solo trip to switzerland.
switzerland was actually my first ever international solo trip.
i went for my 24th birthday two years ago.
and you may be wondering why i never posted that vlog.
well, it's because it was a mess.
to start off, i forgot all of my battery chargers.
i got sick on my first full day there.
my hotel room was infested with bugs so i couldn't sleep.
there was a moment where i thought i was about to to get trafficked, and
I kept getting lost and missed every single train transfer or bus I had scheduled.
Like I said, a mess.
But that was when I was 24.
This year I'm turning 26.
I learned how to use public transportation, and I've been equipped with a fully developed
frontal lobe for a year now, so this time nothing can go wrong.
You're at a fire somewhere, somehow.
Our journey starts at LAX, where I'm currently journaling, and that brings us to the
first mistake I wanted to correct this trip.
last time I flew to Switzerland I had multiple connecting flights which was a nightmare.
I missed one of my connecting flights.
I had to get off the airplane and recheck my bag because apparently if you're
in another country for over two hours then you have to recheck your bag.
you know what I still don't know how it works exactly but it was just
very messy.
I got lost.
did not want to do that again.
this time I made sure to book a non-stop flight which the only airline that
flies direct from LA to Switzerland is swiss airlines.
my original flight was around $800 but swiss airlines has a feature where you can bid
to upgrade.
for context, a business class flight from LA to Switzerland non-stop costs $7,000 one way.
but with the bid upgrade, how it works is you bid how much you'd be
willing to pay for an upgrade.
if your bid gets accepted, you pay that amount and then you get to choose
your business class seat.
but if your bid doesn't get accepted, you don't pay anything extra and you just
keep your original fare.
it's risk-free and it's a really good way to get a business class seat for
more affordable
price.
i
slept
for almost the entire flight which was great because we have a very serious mission
after the plane lands and that's to not get lost on the train.
last time i got lost almost every single time i used the public transportation i
don't know how i got lost going from the airport to my hotel because it
was almost like a direct station but i did and i eventually had to call
an uber so this time i was determined to get it right
i got off at the right station this time but unfortunately i did still get
lost and turned a 10 minute walk into a 30 minute walk so baby steps
i guess
Even
though I got lost and turned a
10 minute walk into a 30 minute walk, I still ended up walking the whole
way instead of calling an Uber.
So proud of myself for that.
I look and smell like a wet dog.
So I'm going to take a shower.
Yay!
I feel so much better now.
Bed bug check.
All clear.
This hotel gave me little biscuits as a gift.
Look how cute.
It's a little house.
I'm kind of nervous about tomorrow.
It's going to be a lot of trains and transfers.
Bye!
I've been up since probably like 3 a.m.
I woke up and couldn't go back to sleep this is my outfit I headed
down for breakfast a little bit too early but this hotel actually has a lot
of community spaces so it was a good time to check out the room with
free beverages
oh they have names I wonder if they have my name let's check
Do they have a Jessica?
David, Nicholas, Arnold...
Jessica!
Yay!
Shh, shh.
Jessica Soda.
Tastes better.
after a very sweet breakfast, it was time to head to mirin!
i was so scared i'd be late for my train that i got there too
early.
so early in fact that i could take the earlier train, so that's what i
ended up doing.
i also got to ride in the restaurant car for the first time, but the
ride was kind of rocky so my coffee kept on spilling.
made for a unique journal entry though.
last time going from zurich to grindelwald, i had missed all but one of my
trains.
3 hours, 3 trains, and a cable car later, we finally made it to miren
and i didn't miss a single transfer.
this was major for me.
i think my hotel is right across from the train station.
Well, this is a car-free town, so there's no cars.
Stairs or a ramp?
We'll just take the stairs.
Ta-da!
This is my room.
Let's go up to the balcony.
This is for staying here for a few nights, I'm gonna
unpack.
I didn't even realize how high up this place is.
Literally in the clouds.
Like look at- outside the window.
Do you see that?
I'm like inside of a cloud right now.
Also what I love about the Swiss Alps is the tap water tastes so good.
It's like the freshest alpine water.
I think I definitely need to go to Coop to pick up some groceries and
food because guys the food in Switzerland is crazy expensive.
Personally, I think Coop tastes really good.
I'm no foodie but the butterzopf was my favorite thing that I got in Switzerland
last time so we're gonna get that today and then I think we're gonna do
the hike towards Gimmelwald.
It's like an easy walk.
Hiking is very nice to North Face Trail or going down to
Gimmelwald.
That's more an easier hike.
I decided to stay in Miren this time because it's a car-free town so it's
less crowded and has more of a small-town feel.
That's not to say it doesn't get crowded though.
During the day, you'll see a lot of tourists but not many of them stay
in the area so it's much quieter in the early mornings and evenings.
I was starving at this point so I stopped by Coop and look at how
much bread and cheese they have, the options are endless.
The walk to Gimmelwald was very easy and peaceful.
It's all along a paved road, so there's really not much to see aside from
the same mountain the whole way, but even just that is beautiful.
Not bad.
The view is great though, you can see a waterfall from here.
You can see the waterfall right there.
Such a beautiful trail.
It took him a while.
At the end, you can take the cable car back to Mirin, or you can
walk back the same way you came.
I made another stop at Coop for a snack and then I stumbled upon this
gift shop.
Honestly, I really wish I had bought something here.
The plushie keychains are so cute.
Oh my god, Switzerland is not for the weak.
God, how am I exhausted from just a walk?
Bed bug check.
Clear.
they're so friendly
Today's a very exciting day because we're doing the North Face Trail hike So I
woke up bright and early to get breakfast Mornings here are very cloudy just because
it's so high up But the clouds usually clear up around noon
When I stepped out, I was shocked to see this cat staring at me.
It was so cute and it started following me, which I wasn't really sure why,
so I stopped to pet it.
And of course, as soon as I gave it some attention, it started walking away.
But it was so cute and it reminds me of Kiki's delivery service with its
red bow.
After saying goodbye to the cat, it's time to head into town to refill my
water and grab a Red Bull before heading to the trailhead.
Now, you can see that there's nobody on this trail, and that's probably the first
red flag I should've caught onto because this is supposed to be a pretty popular
trail.
I thought maybe it was too cloudy or early, people just didn't feel like doing
it at this time.
No, I was doing the alternate route, which is the harder version that starts from
the opposite end, and I went on a 15 minute detour because I thought that
this gate meant private property.
It's not.
It's the start or end of the trail.
Um, slightly alarming update, I'm lost.
I took the wrong turn somewhere.
What the heck, I was right about it being this road the first time.
Oh, it's just no bikes.
This looks more like a trail now.
This trail was definitely more advanced than what I'm used to.
The first two hours were all basically uphill, and there are a lot of trickier
areas with slippery rocks.
Also, another important thing to note is if you do this trail backwards like I
did, it's gonna be very empty.
I think for the first two to three hours I was on this trail, I
didn't see a single other person.
so if you're planning on doing the trail by yourself, it's nice to get some
alone time but also a little bit scary in case anything goes wrong there are
also a decent amount of signs for directions but they can be kind of confusing
because there's so many different trails there are shorter versions of trails that lead you
to the same destination so if you have a specific route you want to follow,
i would just route it on all trails and then use that
even though i got lost on this hike like three times already, pushing through and
finding my way back, it feels even more rewarding So I did the trail backwards.
Wait, am I supposed to turn that way?
Around the fourth or fifth time I got lost on this trail, I just accepted
my fate not to get lost forever, but just to enjoy my surroundings instead of
fixating on whether I'm on the right path or not.
Like I said, there's so many signs, so it's not like you're gonna get lost
on the trail forever.
In worst case, I just retraced my steps and go backwards the way the trail
was supposed to be done.
So yeah, I'm trying to be a girl whatever girl.
You said this trail was moderate on all trails?
You're a liar.
oh
my
god really need to check what the other hikes I planned are because like if
that's moderate like the one i did at lake ball chop that was easy that's
why i was like oh i can do like a step above that but no
if they're all like this i can't i can't do it got the sandwich egg
sandwich so we'll see how it compares to the pan because i love the japanese
egg sandwiches it's not terrible but the japanese ones are definitely better like they don't
give you much egg i feel like so the plan is eat red bull and
then we're gonna head to laocha brunan this is the best red bull flavor by
the way if you haven't had it it reminds me of yakult so good
oh my god i see somebody paragliding outside honestly i don't think i would do
that again i did that last time when i went to grindelwald and it was
not my favorite i also did it when it was cloudy though also when you
do paragliding the way that you get off the ground they pick like a really
high hill and then you guys run off of the hill until the parachute picks
up wind and then it'll carry you off of the ground.
so last time when i did it the instructor that i had was 6'4 i'm
4'11.
it was so frustrating to me because like when we were running off of the
hill he was like yelling at me because i wasn't able to run anymore because
at a certain point you have to think about it if he's 6'4 i'm 4'11
and we're strapped into the same height of a seat at some point if his
feet are on the ground mine are not on the ground anymore because we're running
off of the same incline he was yelling at me he was like run run
i was like i can't anyway the parachute did end up catching wind but i
was just so annoyed
i'm walking around lao chabrun now look at the waterfall this is staubach falls i
think i'm on the way to trumbull back it's actually a pretty long walk it's
like 45 minutes but the walk is pretty nice it's just like one road that
you walk down for the whole time
little baby kitty so i didn't end up actually going to tremelbeck falls i turned
around because i was getting so overstimulated lauterbrunnen is beautiful but it's so crowded and
there's so many cars and because this is just one road with people walking on
both sides you always have to check behind you for cars still it was a
very beautiful walk so if i were to visit again i'd probably try to go
earlier in the morning to skip the crowds.
This is bad.
I can barely walk normally.
Oh my God, I'm so sore.
Tomorrow's plan was to go to Lake Oschinensee, that hike, but
that one also says moderate.
I mainly wanted to swim, but I'm still on my period.
So we'll see.
So change of plans.
This morning has been a mess because one of the trains are down that heads
to Interlaken, which is the central place that connects all of the places I wanted
to go to so instead we're gonna go to Wengen and- er, Wengen and then
go to Grindelwald after I had to change my outfit and re-wear this top because
I can't wear the stuff that I was planning to wear to the Oshinen Lake
I went to Grindelwald last time but I haven't been to Wengen so hopefully it's
nice
We can go to the main lake near the end of the trip.
Vingen's a small, quiet town.
Honestly, I don't know if it's the time that I went, but there really wasn't
much to do there.
But from here, you can go up to mainlaken, which is also the connect to
Grindelwald.
And despite not being planned, mainlaken ended up being one of the highlights of my
trip.
There's two lakes and hiking trails.
I see a bunch of cows down there, so this is like, I mean, I
can't say it's better than Osterman Lake because I've never been, but This is pretty
pretty cool.
Oh my god, you see that first cow
I'm going to the bathroom.
It's the bathroom.
2월 30일 10시 후
8시 저절로
그에 접근할 때가 많아요
제작진의 전화기 욕실에 들으면 버스가 오면 뭐 그냥 저을건데
마지막에 이곳에 갔었던 곳은 뷔스폰이었어요
아 네, 제가 가게에 가고, 그리고 이곳에서 가장 큰 잘못을 한 게 바로 이 여행을
한 것 같아요 먼저, 저는 탑워드를 사지 않고 물을 사지 않고 잘못을 했었어요 그래서 제가
물을 차지해서 그 한 잔의 물을 3달러에 구입했어요 참고로 탑워드와 같은 맛이에요, 여기 탑워드가 정말
맛있죠 그리고 이건 그들이 잘못한 게 아니라, 그들은 정말 아무것도 안 하는 것 같아요 여름에
외국에서 많이 먹었지만 여기에는 너무 많은 새가 있었어요 이 식당은 가장 좋은 경험이 아니었어요 특히
저는 이 식당에서 50달러를 받는 걸 알았기 때문에 그냥 좋은 외국 식당이었고 그리고 새가 온다니..
밥을 다 먹었을 때, 저는 좀 부족했기 때문에 호텔에 바로 돌아갔어요
이곳은
스파와 렐렉세이션 공간이에요.
아무도 사용하지 않나요?
그 뒤에가 운동실이에요.
이 호텔을 구경할 시간이 없었지만 최근에 renovations를 했었고 이 스파 공간을 추가했었죠.
제가 정말 좋아한 것 같아요.
그래서 여기에서 좀 쉬고 잠시 쉬기 전에 잠을 자요.
조금 아프게 깨어났는데 오늘이 정말興기 때문에 도착했어요 네, 도착했어요 이 시계로 안녕
잘 구경하는 중
타깃
다시 가야할 것 같은 느낌
2, 4, 5
오이, 이거 더 좋아 보인다고 생각했죠 조거장
그리고 이 두 번째 작은 책이 여기에요
그리고 여기가 카우즈에요 솔직히 말해서 이건 제가 예상해보기엔 더 넓은 곳이에요
여기가 커피 바가고 그리고 이걸로 냉장고가 보러가보면 와아아아아아
그리고 오늘 너무 깨끗하게 보이네요
벨크가 엄청 커요 사진 찍을때 기대되요 그리고 이제 화장실을 열어볼게요 화장실
이 액젓을 가지고 싶어요?
아니면 토플레온을?
이 건강한 결정은 제가 해야겠어요
여기에서 여행하시면 프리 픽업 서비스를 요청해주세요 트레인에서 배달을 받을 수 있어요 스위스에서 저번에 여행한 호텔에서
서비스를 받았어요
그래서 제가 한 분씩 걸을게요
그리고 정말 어려운 걸을 했고
호텔에 오면 아주 깊은 길이거든요 그래서 저는 그 수케스를 항상 들고 있는 과정에 대해서 이미
고민하고 있어요 그래서 이 방을 제가 체이스 트러블 포인트에 주문했어요 체이스 트러블 카드가 있으면 체이스
사파이어 리저브가 있어요 제가 카드 포인트에 대해서는 말할 수 없지만
제가 체이스 트러블 포털을 통해 호텔을 주문하면 체이스 트러블 포털이 더 잘 구성되고
.
예를 들어, 여기가 제주도에서 주문한 방이 있었습니다.
최스의 마지막으로.
저는 기대할수록 훨씬 좋았고, 특히 시장의 방들은 작아질 수 있습니다.
최스는 호텔에서 호텔을 제공하고, 어떤 소재의 주택을 받을 수 있고, 호텔의 지급을 받을 수 있습니다.
하지만, 이는 그들의 여행 포털에서 주문한 방이기 때문에, 그래서 저는 이 호텔에서 주문한 호텔, 레조르
레지나 벨을 사용하셨습니다.
그리고 당신의 카드와 포인트에 대해서도 돈을 받을 수 있습니다.
스위스압에서 저는 항상 호텔과 벨크니를 주문하고 싶어요.
여기가 너무 아름다워서 벨크니를 가지고 있는 것은 정말 비싼 것 같아요.
하지만, 예, 저는 모르게 이 제품을 사용해봤어요 선크림이 다시 도착했어요 메이크업을 한 번 해봤어요 이제
갈게요
엑셀트
여기 걸어서 걸을 수 있는 곳인가요?
카운트포인트의 한 장을 처음 봤어요
조각 조각 와우
매우 조그만
이게 초콜릿이에요 어느 날은 다른 사람이 가져왔어요 음...
맥주가 들어있어서 한번 먹어볼까요?
그리고...
쿠프가 옆에 있어요
아 이거 너무 귀여워요 이거?
이거요?
이건 제가 좋아하는 거에요 이거 가져가세요 가져가세요
아, 이거 너무 맛있어 아, 이거 너무 맛있어 커피맥을 사용해야지 물을 끓여야죠
물을 끓여야죠 오!
오!
특히 지금 아프니까 이곳이 바로 맞을 것 같아요
5라운드 5라운드
5라운드 5라운드 오늘의 주인공 좋은
아침이에요!
오늘의 생일이니까요 아침이 더 예쁜 것 같아요
오늘의 첫 번째 옷은 제가 원하는 옷이에요 Fp무브먼트 이거 룩북 하이킹 재킷이에요 사실
이 옷은 이 옷의 길이도 맞춰서
그리고 후디도 룩북 하이킹 재킷이에요 귀엽죠?
이번엔 이거랑 같이 이거랑 같이?
네, 완벽해 손은 90도로 가야해 손을?
네, 이렇게 90도로 중요해 그리고 백팩 백팩 하나 감사합니다
배터리, 배터리 팩
지금 도착했습니다
821을 만들 수 있을 것 같아요
마치 기가 막히는 느낌
제가 지금 도망가는 이유는
젊은이들이 매터의 그의 발을 보게 되는 첫번째 호수를 향하고 싶어요 매터의 발을 보게 되면 아침에
매우 늦게 일어날 수 있어요 낮에는 너무 많은 사람들이 있으니까 사람들이 롯드와 동물을 던지고, 물이
올라오고, 발을 보게 되는 게 아니라
그의 발을 보게 되는 게 좋습니다 이 숲에는 전기기 세팅이 필요합니다.
소음이 생기지 않도록 과연 소음이 생기는 날이 없을까?
우리 집은 마치 아이스 아메리카노가 되는 대로 구조화 된 곳이다.
이곳은 두개의 시장에서 일한 시장으로 들어간 곳이다.
이곳은 수진이 생긴 시장이지만, 요즘 8시 반에 일어나고 있다.
그 곳은 8시 40분이다.
마지막까지 일어나기 전에 일을 하자.
저희는 그곳에 위치해 다른 곳으로 돌아가도록 같이 가야한다.
이곳은 한국의 한 대중교통기구에 있는 한국국토정보공사입니다.
there, we'll go on a hike too.
This way.
Guess this is a popular trail.
There are a lot of signs everywhere.
Which is good.
Because I get lost easily.
I realized I was on the wrong trail pretty early on this time.
It was getting really steep and like the North Face Trail, I saw online that
this one was family-friendly, so I knew something was wrong.
Ah, there's the first lane.
I caught up with this German couple who also took the wrong route and they
were so nice, they offered to take these videos for me.
Finally, after an hour, we made it to Stella Sea, and yes, there is still
a reflection.
Not a bad lunch view.
I
think around 11 something is when there's no more reflection.
I need to recover as soon as possible.
I do not want to be like this all day
Let's take some birthday photos
I know I made a big fuss about eating out in Switzerland but it's my
birthday so I had to book a dinner.
eating out is actually one of the few things I do not enjoy doing by
myself maybe it's because I'm not a huge foodie so going out and trying new
foods by myself isn't something I would normally enjoy doing so I did feel the
weight of being alone more in this moment yeah I think this is the first
time on this trip where I actually felt lonely but it was a great meal
nonetheless
let's go explore I saw some souvenirs I wanted to look at
I saw these on the trail today.
Let's see how much they are.
$8.90.
I think that's like $10.
I want the...
Oh, there's the black-nosed sheep.
Happy birthday, girl.
Thank you.
Oh, you're going to the shop?
Oh, my God, this place is so beautiful.
Since I'm 26 now, I realized I won't be able to eat whatever I want
for much longer, so I treated myself to whatever pastries I wanted to try at
breakfast.
You're literally going for all the pastries.
I don't like it.
Where's your protein, bro?
A donut?
You're eating just some pastries.
The jam filling.
Okay.
One more.
It's my last day in Switzerland so I decided to try my luck at finding
the black-nosed sheep.
The shepherd has been sick for the past two days so nobody's been able to
see them but you can track them online and I saw they were active between
Riffle Alp and Riffleburg so I bought a ticket to Riffleburg.
They seem to be closer to Riffle Alp though so I got off the station
earlier.
Got off at Riffle Alp and the hunt for the sheep begins.
Honestly though, this map hasn't been updated since like an hour ago so I hope
they're still somewhere in this area.
It's pretty surreal hiking, seeing stuff like this.
this hotel's so pretty.
perhaps i should have stopped in riffleburg so i could hike down.
i decided i'm just gonna walk straight back to the station, take it up to
riffleburg, and hike down.
because since the train goes up all the way to gornigrad, if you get off
early you have to hike up, if you get off at the next stop you
hike down.
so we're gonna do the downhill hike.
i also didn't realize this was an actual hike so i do have the hiking
backpack today but my outfit is not really giving hiking, it's giving she wanted to
take pictures with the sheep.
yeah i honestly don't know how i do it but as soon as i got
off at the next station i started going the wrong way again but this is
when i discovered a new hiking hack you find two people who look like they
know what they're doing and then you just try your best to keep up with
them this trail is mostly made of very smooth rocks and i learned you don't
want to step on top of them you want to step on like a corner
because they're very sandy so they get very slippery there they are i did get
off the station too early but technically i didn't get lost so they usually recommend
you come earlier in the morning.
that's usually when the sheep are the most friendly.
i came in the afternoon so they were all a little tired.
most of them were pressing their face against a rock.
even though it wasn't super sunny, they do this to cool down because they have
that iconic black nose that gets really hot in the sun.
fighting.
i think
we came from all the way up there
it's getting late and i still need to head back to zurich so it's time
to head back to town and grab some chocolates on the walk back i saw
another street cat and the cats in switzerland are so friendly This one was so
cute, I was so tempted to take her home with me
And with that, my Switzerland do-over trip has come to an end So the main
takeaway is that I am still very much directionally challenged No, but actually, I set
out on this trip to fix all of my mistakes from my last trip so
that I could create the perfect version of it.
And then of course, things still went wrong.
But strangely, in those moments where I got lost, I got sick, the train stopped
running, I really started developing more confidence and trust in myself.
In my daily life, I'm not much of an adventurer or somebody who takes risks.
And I get frustrated when I don't get things right the first time.
But whenever I solo travel, I'm forced to deal with these situations and I realize
how capable I am.
Even though I got lost so many times on this trip, I was also able
to find my way back all those times.
So maybe more important than always getting everything right is trusting yourself enough to know
that even when things fall apart, you'll figure it out.
And refuse to shine Baby, would I still be your lover?
Would you want me there if the moon went dark tonight?
And if it all ended tomorrow Would I be the one on your mind?
On my, on my And if it all ended tomorrow Would I be
the one on your mind?
you